Uchiha Sasuke...
オイラが殺すはずだった
大蛇丸をやりやがった➡
I can't forgive him
'cuz he killed Orochimaru,
うちはサスケを許せねえ！
whom I planned to kill!
Release!
《喝！》
いい目で睨みやがってるぜ トビ！
Tobi, look how he's glaring at us!
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Clash!
(サスケ)うちはイタチは どこだ？
Where's Uchiha Itachi?
(デイダラ)は？
Huh?
言えば見逃してやる。
Tell me, and I'll let you go.
(デイダラ)写輪眼か…。
やっぱりコイツ イタチの弟だぜ。
Sharingan... eh?
He really is Itachi's younger brother.
大蛇丸をやれたのも うちはの血の
おかげってわけだ… うん。
You were only able to kill Orochimaru
thanks to your Uchiha blood.
血統に恵まれただけの
勘違い野郎が！
You're nothing but a fool
blessed with good genes!
《速い！》
(トビ)え？
He's fast!
Huh?!
まずは１匹。
One down.
よくしゃべるお前には
イタチのことを…。
So I'll ask you,
the one with the big mouth, about Itachi.
何やってんだ トビ！
ガキだからって気抜くなよ。 うん！
What're you doing, Tobi?!
Don't let your guard down
just because he's a kid!
瞬身の術が速すぎて
ボクらじゃムリっすよ～。
His Teleportation Jutsu is too quick.
We're no match for him!
《コイツ！》
That guy...!
ヘッ！
《まずは チャクラレベルＣ１で
動きを見てやる》
First, I'll watch his movements
with chakra level C1.
トビ！ 下がってろ!!
Tobi! Stay back!
わぁ！ うわ～！
うわぁ～！
せせ… 先輩 タイム！
S-Senpai! Time out!
喝は やっちゃダメ！
チッ！
Don't do it!
先輩 後ろ後ろ！
Senpai! Behind you, behind you!
喝！
Release!
先輩！
Senpai!
あぁ…。
厳しい先輩だったけど
いい先輩だったなぁ。
He was strict, but a good partner...
ボクは決して デイダラ先輩のことを…。
I shall never forget about you,
Deidara-senpai--!
ギャーギャーうるせえぞ！
え？
Will you shut up?!
あ～ 生きてた。
Oh, you're alive?
《掌から爆発物を作る能力か…》
The ability to produce
an explosive with his palm, huh?
《爆風で どうにか逃げ切れた。
I somehow managed to escape
by hiding in the bomb blast...
練り込んだチャクラをＣ１にしといて
助かったぜ… うん》
Good thing I kept
the chakra level at C1.
《確かに動きは速いが
コイツはどうだ？》
He definitely moves swiftly...
How about this then?
もうちょっと遊んでやるぜ。
うん！
I'll play with you a bit more!
子供だましか？
Child's play?
くだらん。
So stupid.
ハハハハ！ まだまだ!!
It's not over yet!
ハハッ！ ハハハハ！
そろそろ… いくか。
I guess... it's about time.
ウソ!?
あ？
No way!
Huh?
だよね～。
おい！
Yeah, I thought so.
Hey...!
どうだ！
あら～。
How's that?!
Oh...
やっぱ たいしたことねえな うん。
He's not much, after all...
やっぱり！
I knew it!
おい トビ！
テメエは どっちの味方なんだよ！
Hey, Tobi!
Whose side are you on anyway?!
《デイダラ : 変わり身の術か…。
A Substitution Jutsu, eh?
確かに 結構やりやがるな。
Well, he's definitely quite skilled...
なら ここは Ｃ２がベスト》
Then this calls for C2.
あっ！ そ そ… それは！
Th-That's...!
出た～！
先輩の十八番芸術のひとつ➡
Ta-daa! One of Senpai's signature
art pieces, the C2 Dragon!
Ｃ２ドラゴン！
わかってんな？ トビ！
Tobi, you know what to do, right?!
もちろんっすよ 先輩！
アレですね？
Of course, Senpai!
We're going with "that", right?!
そうだ！
その アレでいくぞ うん！
Yeah! "That" is the plan...
《あのでかいのも
爆発物になりえるのか？》
That huge thing becomes
an explosive too?
任せたぞ トビ！
オッス！
I'm counting on you, Tobi!
Right!
《しかも あの形状からして➡
And judging from its looks,
it'll be attacking from the sky...!
空からか… 厄介だ》
This is bad.
来た～！
Here he comes!
Let's show him, Senpai...
先輩のポップアートの力
見せつけてやりましょうよ！
The power of your pop art!
ポップは死んだ！ オイラのは…。
Pop art is dead! My art is...
スーパーフラットだ！
Superflat!
喝！
Release!
《さっきとは違う… 誘導弾か》
It's different from before...
A guided missile?
《もう一人が いない。
Where's the other one?
とりあえずは アイツか！》
Guess I'll start off with him!
《フンッ 伸ばせる限界は
５メートルってとこか》
Looks like it can only reach up
to five meters, eh?
《チッ… 間合いを見切られたか》
Tsk... He figured out my limit.
カカシのだろ？ それ。
That's Kakashi's trick right?!
伸ばしたり 投げたりって
形状変化は 認めてやるがよ。
I'll give you credit for the skill in
changing chakra form to extend and throw.
コイツは さっきのとは
威力が違うぜ。
But the force of this one's different
from earlier.
吹き飛べ！
Blow to bits!
《さすがに速いな。
He really is swift.
かかった！》
Got him!
やったか。
Did I get him...?
《デイダラ : あれは… 大蛇丸の呪印か。
That's... Orochimaru's Curse Mark!
翼まで生えるとはな。
He can even grow wings?
上手く 上へ飛んで かわしたか》
He managed to dodge it
by flying upwards...
先輩！ 地雷粘土
すべて セッティング オーケーッス！
Senpai! All the land mine clay is set
and ready to go!
(デイダラ)よくやった トビ！
お前は 離れてろ！
Good job, Tobi! You stay back.
オッス！
Yessir!
《上からは 誘導弾
下からは 地雷か》
Guided missile attacks from above,
and land mines from the ground!
Ｃ２は 地雷の足止めと
空中からの ピンポイント攻撃。
The key element of
the C2 coordinated assault
is using the land mines
to slow you down
この連係攻撃が ミソだ。
and finishing you off with
a pinpoint missile attack.
お前の足元には すでに
ビッシリ地雷が 敷き詰めてある。
Land mines are planted all around you!
踏みつけただけで 自動爆破だ。
Step on one and you'll set them off!
《誘導弾を 確実に当てるためか。
He plans to ram the guided missile
right into me.
オレの攻撃範囲の外を➡
And it's flying just outside
my attack perimeter...
ギリギリまで 近づいて飛んでやがる》
その 負傷した足で➡
With that wounded leg,
オレの 空中からの攻撃を
上手くかわせるかな？ うん。
I wonder if you can dodge
my aerial attack... hmm?
次のは でかいぜ！ うん！
The next one's gonna be big!
飛ばせるか！
As if I'll let you fly away!
喝！
Release
ハハッ 翼でガードなんかすっから➡
That's what you get for trying to
guard yourself with wings.
もう 飛べねえな 片翼じゃあよ。
ハハハ！
You can't fly anymore, can you?
Not with one wing...
さすが デイダラ先輩！
You're awesome, Deidara-senpai!
これで 終わりにしてやるぜ！
うん！
Well, let's settle this!
そんなもんが 当たるか！
As if that'll hit me!
《ヘヘッ 足場なし。
No foothold! Fall on a land mine
and you'll lose a limb for sure!
地雷原に落ちたら
どこかは もげるぜ 確実にな》
《あ 足場!?》
A-A foothold?!
《なに!? 届いただと!?》
What?!
He reached me?
バランスが！
Deidara's balance...!
《コイツ 刀を わざと地面に!?
He purposely stuck his sword
in the ground?
地雷の有無を確かめ
足場を作った。
He tested for the presence of land mines
and created a foothold?!
足場にした 刀の長さの分➡
The length of the sword,
which he used as a foothold...
それに 片翼を使ったジャンプ。
And that jump using his single wing...
こ この位置…！
This position?!
そうか あの攻撃で 刀の真上に
オイラを誘い込み…》
I see. With that attack,
he lured me directly above the sword...
《チャクラ刀の届く 最短距離を…》
The shortest distance that
a chakra sword would reach...
うわぁ！
先輩！
Senpai!
《クッ！ 動けねえ！》
I can't move...!
《ヤバイ… 下には 地雷が！》
This is bad!
Below me are the land mines...!
うわぁっ！
先輩！
Senpai!!
やっぱ最後は爆死じゃないっすか。
テイダラ先輩のバカ野郎！
You did die by bombing, after all!
Deidara-senpai... you fool!
ギャーギャーうるせえって
言ってんだ。 トビ。
I keep telling you to shut up, Tobi!
ま まだ生きてた。
Huh? Y-You're still alive...?
しぶとい。
What a stubborn...
((ああっ！
(うっ))
この… クソガキが！
You... damn kid!
《あの眼。 あの眼だ》
Those eyes...
It's those same eyes...
《デイダラ : チクショウ！》
Damn it!
((暁だ？ 知るか そんなもん。
"Akatsuki"?
Like I care! Don't interfere with
my appreciation of art.
オイラのアート鑑賞を
ジャマするんじゃねえ。
(サソリ)こんなガキを オレの連れに
しなきゃなんねえのか。
And I'm supposed to take
this kid as my partner...?
威勢はいいが コイツは
早死にするタイプだぜ。
He's feisty, but looks like
the type to die young.
(イタチ)リーダーの命令だ。
コイツの能力は役に立つ。
It's our leader's orders...
We can use his powers.
オイラの能力を知ってんのか？
お前ら いったい？
You know about my power?
Just who the hell are...?
(鬼鮫)近隣諸国で
反国家分子どもに加担して➡
You're the bomb terrorist
who's been supporting
爆破テロを起こしているのは
あなたですね。
the anti-government factions
in various lands.
抜け忍のあなたが
何の目的でそんなことを？
What purpose would that serve
a rogue ninja like you...?
目的？
そんなもんありゃしねえよ。
Purpose? I have no purpose!
オイラは依頼を受けて
爆発を起こすだけだ。
I get requests to set off explosions,
so I do.
オイラの作品でな。
With my creations!
作品？
そうだ。
Creations?
That's right.
見ろ。 どうだ。
Look!
Well? Such refined lines,
この洗練されたラインに
二次元的なデフォルメを追求した造形。
and a form that pursues
two-dimensional deform.
まさにアートだ。
This  is art!
だが オイラのアートは
これだけじゃない。
But that's not all there is to my art!
オイラの作品は流動的だ。
My creations flow!
形あるときは
ただの造形物にすぎない。 うん。
When it has shape,
it's simply molded clay!
これは爆発する。
But this explodes!
その爆発により
その存在を昇華させて➡
And the explosion causes sublimation,
初めて本来の作品になる。
and for the first time,
the essence of my creation appears!
That instant of sublimation is
when I experience true art!
オイラはその一瞬の昇華にこそ
アートを感じてならない。 うん。
芸術は爆発なのだ！
Art is an explosion!
うざいな。
終わりですか？
How annoying...
Is he done?
さあな。
Who knows...
もういい。 オレがやろう。
Never mind... I'll do it.
《なんだ あの目？》
What's with his eyes...?
やろうってのか!?
You wanna fight?
オレが勝ったら
お前は暁に入ってもらう。
If I win,
you will become a member of Akatsuki.
オイラを… アートをナメんじゃねえぞ！
Don't belittle... me... or my art!
オレの忍術は
何よりも崇高な芸術だ。 うん！
My ninjutsu is nothing
but noble, refined art!
アートを感じろ！
Feel my art!
喝！
Release
ヘヘッ！ いきがってたわりには
その程度かよ。
You talked big...
but is that all you have?
終わりだ。 うん！
It's over!
よく自分の姿を見たほうがいい。
You should take a good look
at yourself.
え？
Huh?
な… なに!?
Wh-What?!
(鬼鮫)危なかったですね。
That was close.
もう少しで
自爆するところでしたよ。
A little later and
you would've blown yourself up.
(サソリ)やっぱり
早死にするタイプだな コイツは。
I told you he was the type to die young.
幻術か！ いつの間に？
A Genjutsu! When?!
初めからですよ。
From the very beginning.
イタチさんの写輪眼を見たとき
すでに あなたは幻術の中。
From the moment you looked
into Itachi's Sharingan,
you were under his Genjutsu.
《デイダラ : 美しい…》
Beautiful...
《デイダラ : これは 芸術だ…》
This is... art!
《チッ… オイラが他人の能力に
見入っちまうなんて。
Damn! I became fascinated
by the abilities of another?
あれが芸術だと？
いや認めねえ… 認めねえぞ！》
That's art? No way...
I refuse to acknowledge it!
お前の負けだ。
You lose.
《ふざけるな…
オイラのほうが上だ！》
Don't mess with me!
I'm better than you!
《オイラの能力は完璧だ。
誰にも負けない芸術だ！》
My ability is flawless...
It's art that is unbeatable!
《オイラのほうが上だ！
負けるはずがねえ！》
I'm better than you! I can't lose...!
(デイダラ)あんな…。
Lose to such a...
あんな!!
Lose to such a...!
あ！ 起爆粘土を自分の口で
食ってるってことは…。
Huh?! He's eating the Detonation Clay,
which means...
とっておきだ！ 次で殺す！
I saved the best for last!
I'll kill you with this!
トビ 逃げてろ！
Tobi, get away!
うわ ヤベー！ Ｃ４カルラだ！
Whoa, yikes!
It's the C4 Karura!
急げ～！
Hurry!
《イタチを殺すための とっておきの
術だったんだがな… うん》
This was supposed to be
my trump card to kill Itachi, but...
なに!?
What?!
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
Next Episode
Wow, the enemy is pretty strong.
He's not Itachi-san's younger brother for nothing.
But boy, Senpai sure is fired up.
Flying, exploding and falling.
(マカロフ)
これまでの 『FAIRY TAIL』は…。
(ミラジェーン)子供の頃から
ナツと仲のよかったリサーナは➡
At this rate, he'll really have
to apologize to Itachi-san later.
ある事件の際に
死んだと思われていたの。
Wow? W-Wait a minute, Senpai!
私たちは
その悲しみを乗り越えて➡
Could that possibly be the...?
なんとか歩き出した。
Ayeee...! No no no!
(ナツ)で エドラスで
リサーナと再会したわけだ。
Please don't say "release" just yet!
しかも
こっちのリサーナだったんだよな。
Next time: "Art"
Art